Ashraf Chowdhury

New York, USA · ashrafchowdhury302@gmail.com · (737) 402 - 9557

https://akc302.github.io/ashraf-portfolio/ www.linkedin.com/in/akc302/ www.github.com/akc302 ·

With three plus years of software industry experience, and one year of teaching experience in Computer Science & Engineering, currently looking for opportunities in a progressive organization to enhance my knowledge and utilize my skills towards the growth of the company.

EDUCATION

United International University - Dhaka, Bangladesh

March 2021

Bachelor's Degree – Computer Science And Engineering, CGPA: 3.98 / 4.00

Excelled in courses: Object-Oriented Programming, Data Structure and Algorithm, DBMS, OS, Software Engineering, Mathematics

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Java, Python, JavaScript, C, C++, PHP, Assembly, JSON, XML, LaTeX, SQL

Technologies: AWS (IAM, ELB & ASG, EC2, S3, Databases & Analytics)

Framework/Libraries (React, React-Native, Bootstrap, Node.js, jQuery, Express)
Database (MySQL, MongoDB, Google Firebase, PostgreSQL, DynamoDB)
Tools (Git, VS Code, Trello, JIRA, MS Project, IntelliJ, Eclipse, Android Studio)
Methodologies (REST, Agile, Microservices, Continuous Integration/Deployment)

WORK EXPERIENCE

HeavyTask - Texas, USA

June 2022 - Present

Junior Software Developer (Remote)

- Closely supporting WebOps, Back-end Java Developers, Designers, Project Managers, and QA Analysts to meet project deadlines.
- Supporting senior developers with updates of existing code base and debugged codes received from the quality assurance team.
- Working on a cloud-based software which is designed for the dumpster rental industry.
 Working on an improvement feature of the GPS Route Tracking System which is making revenues.
 - [URL: https://fleetpros.co/]

• Leveraged GIT to collaborate with team members.

Delta Developer - Dhaka, Bangladesh

May 2018 - June 2021

Software Developer

- Automated creation of ServiceNow tickets which helped in reducing the number of calls to the internal helpdesk.
- Designed web application to easily view and manage customers' personal and order information using PHP and MySQL facilitating faster customer support.
- Implemented Java Object-Oriented Solution using SQL, a relational database mapper, to increase re-usability and modularity while decreasing debug time.
- Led the cost optimization initiative that resulted in annual savings.
- Developed application to visualize customer order and user experience in travel agency websites using React.js and Node.js.

[URL: http://meghpeonbd.com/]

- Collaborated with Client DevOps teams during design, build, test and release phases of feature development. Provided deliverable report as a retrospective task after completion of each project.
- Implemented weather pull feature using open weather API, React.js for a client's project.
- Built a machine learning approach model to predict heart disease in a web application feature.

Northern University Bangladesh - Dhaka, Bangladesh

June 2021 - May 2022

Lecturer

- Create multiple groups of software teams and lead them to develop web & mobile applications.
- Supervised projects led by students on building effective market-facing productivity software and guided them with market-penetration strategy and teamwork.
- Provide lectures on Object-Oriented Programming, Data Structure & Algorithm Analysis, Web Development, System Analysis And Design courses, Structure Programming Language for in-person class and sometimes remotely.
- Published conference paper in Springer link on detecting bangla social media hate speech.

[URL:https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-981-19-2445-3 50]